<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Filbar</title><link>https://filbar-music.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Filbar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 15:13:10 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filbar-music.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modular Jamming</title><link>https://filbar-music.github.io/posts/20220327-modular-jamming/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 15:13:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://filbar-music.github.io/posts/20220327-modular-jamming/</guid><description>When I started venturing from software to hardware synthesizers I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was doing, nor did I know what I wanted to do with them. I just wanted something more tactile to play and learn with. &amp;hellip; and it had to be analog, for soem reason I had at the time. So I started building DIY kits and learning. Originally I treated it like an instrument. I could record parts of a song into a DAW and go from there.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://filbar-music.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 15:35:51 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://filbar-music.github.io/about/</guid><description>My name is Filbar. I make noise. I may even call some of that noise music.
Stringed instruments and semiconductors are my weapons of choice; patch cables slung over my shoulders like bandoliers and picks slowly accumulating into spent ammunition piles at my feet.</description></item><item><title>Tonelab LE as a MIDI Controller</title><link>https://filbar-music.github.io/posts/tonelab-le-as-a-midi-board/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 15:13:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://filbar-music.github.io/posts/tonelab-le-as-a-midi-board/</guid><description>Years ago I bought a VOX ToneLab LE to augment the collection of dedicated guitar effects that I was using. Fast forward a lot of years, I have sold nearly all my original guitar pedals but I still have two: my original CryBaby (I mean, how could I part with it?!?) and the ToneLab LE (because no one wanted to buy it).
The ToneLab however has become an integral part to my digital workflows because apart from being a multi-fx pedal it also has MIDI in/out and can be wired up to control all manner of things.</description></item></channel></rss>