<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Filbar</title><link>https://filbar-music.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Filbar</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 15:13:10 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filbar-music.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modular Jamming</title><link>https://filbar-music.github.io/posts/20220327-modular-jamming/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 15:13:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://filbar-music.github.io/posts/20220327-modular-jamming/</guid><description>When I started venturing from software to hardware synthesizers I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I was doing, nor did I know what I wanted to do with them. I just wanted something more tactile to play and learn with. &amp;hellip; and it had to be analog, for reason I had at the time. So I started building DIY kits and learning. Originally I treated it like an instrument. I could record parts of a song into a DAW and go from there.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I started venturing from software to hardware synthesizers I didn&rsquo;t know what I was doing, nor did I know what I wanted to do with them.  I just wanted something more tactile to play and learn with.  &hellip; and it had to be analog, for reason I had at the time.  So I started building DIY kits and learning.  Originally I treated it like an instrument.  I could record parts of a song into a DAW and go from there.  But the more that I played with it, the more I just wanted to play with it, to get a solid groove going and just ride it.</p>
<p>Turns out that isn&rsquo;t quite so easy to do when you have a small handful of exclusively analog modules ¯\<em>(ツ)</em>/¯.</p>
]]></content></item><item><title>Tonelab LE as a MIDI Controller</title><link>https://filbar-music.github.io/posts/tonelab-le-as-a-midi-board/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 15:13:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://filbar-music.github.io/posts/tonelab-le-as-a-midi-board/</guid><description>Years ago I bought a VOX ToneLab LE to augment the collection of dedicated guitar effects that I was using. Fast forward a lot of years, I have sold nearly all my original guitar pedals but I still have two: my original CryBaby (I mean, how could I part with it?!?) and the ToneLab LE (because no one wanted to buy it).
The ToneLab however has become an integral part to my digital workflows because apart from being a multi-fx pedal it also has MIDI in/out and can be wired up to control all manner of things.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Years ago I bought a VOX ToneLab LE to augment the collection of dedicated guitar effects that I was using. Fast forward a lot of years, I have sold nearly all my original guitar pedals but I still have two: my original CryBaby (I mean, how could I part with it?!?) and the ToneLab LE (because no one wanted to buy it).</p>
<p>The ToneLab however has become an integral part to my digital workflows because apart from being a multi-fx pedal it also has MIDI in/out and can be wired up to control all manner of things. I routinely use it with Bias FX on an iPad as a mobile guitar rig or connected to Bitwig to control effects with the expression pedal.</p>
<p>But it doesn&rsquo;t work perfectly straight out of the box since it will you will only get MIDI for program changes and the expression pedal.  I am documenting this here mainly for myself—for the next time I reset it—but maybe it&rsquo;ll help someone else out.</p>
<h2 id="program-vs-effects-modes">Program vs Effects Modes</h2>
<p>First off it helps to understand the two modes and what types of MIDI signals each will send.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Program Mode: this is where you can select between different preconfigured effects stored in the banks.  This is the default mode and the 1-4 toggles will show red LEDs in this mode.  In this mode the 1-4 toggles will only send program change codes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Effect Mode: This lets you toggle individual effects of the currently selected program.  To enter Effects mode press and hold the &ldquo;Bank Up&rdquo; toggle and you will see the LEDs turn green.  You are now in effects mode and the 1-4 toggles will send change control codes (once you enable it).</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="configuring-the-tonelab-le-for-midi">Configuring The ToneLab LE For MIDI</h2>
<p>Out of the box you get program changes and the expression pedal but no control codes for the toggles. So you have to do a bit <a href="ToneLab_LE_Manual.pdf">RTFMing</a> to get this to work. Open the manual and start reading at page 50. :)</p>
<p>In short you have to: 1) enable sending CC MIDI messages, and 2) assign CC #s to the different toggles.</p>
<ol>
<li>With your ToneLab on, press the global button to get into settings.  Press the left (<code>&lt;</code>) or right (<code>&gt;</code>) arrow buttons to navigate and set <code>CCHG I/O</code> to <code>on</code></li>
</ol>

    <img src="cchngon.jpeg"  class="left"  />


<ol start="2">
<li>now press both the left and the right buttons at the same time (<code>&lt;</code> + <code>&gt;</code>) to access further parameters and set the MIDI settings for each control switch.</li>
</ol>
<p>For reference here are my settings:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Function</th>
<th>Setting</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Exp pedal</td>
<td>CC06</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Ctrl</td>
<td>CC05</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pedal</td>
<td>CC01</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Modulation</td>
<td>CC02</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Delay</td>
<td>CC04</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Reverb</td>
<td>CC05</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Insert</td>
<td>CC07</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Amp Ctrl</td>
<td>CC09</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Cab Ctrl</td>
<td>CC10</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

    <img src="expcc.jpeg"  class="left"  />


<p>The rest is up to you.  Connect to your computer and configure your DAW or Audio app to use the MIDI controller your liking.</p>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>